<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ag Alewerks</title>
    <link>https://agalewerks.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ag Alewerks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agalewerks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strisselspalt Pilsner</title>
      <link>https://agalewerks.com/beers/strisselspaltpilsner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agalewerks.com/beers/strisselspaltpilsner/</guid>
      <description>Strisselspalt Pilsner The inspiartion for our new for Bluebonnet Brew-off 2019 pilsner came from a beverage that we sampled while vacationing in Virginia. A former Dallas area brewer had taken up shop at Wort Hog Brewing so we ducked in to see what Jeremy had gotten himself into.
We sampled the current wares and I was smitten by the BECKHAM STREET – HOPPY PILSNER. The “hoppy” bit derived from using a French hop – Strisselspalt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thistle Dew</title>
      <link>https://agalewerks.com/beers/thistledew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agalewerks.com/beers/thistledew/</guid>
      <description>Thistle Dew Scottish Export Ale Impression BJCP describes a Scottich Export as
A malt-focused, generally caramelly beer with perhaps a few esters and occasionally a butterscotch aftertaste. Hops only to balance and support the malt. The malt character can range from dry and grainy to rich, toasty, and caramelly, but is never roasty and especially never has a peat smoke character. The Story This beer was born out of a “Hopped Challenge” sponsored by Cobra Brewing in Lewisville, Texas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingredients</title>
      <link>https://agalewerks.com/post/ingredients/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agalewerks.com/post/ingredients/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients I was flattered recently when a beer friend asked for my thoughts on the importance of each ingredient in beer. Normally beer has just four ingredients – water, barley, hops, and yeast – and with them a very wide variety of flavors can be created.
Water Everything starts with water. If you aren’t able to change the composition of the water, you should choose styles that suit water available. Since the drinking water in North Texas is sourced from Army Corp of Engineers reservoirs and subject to seasonal changes I suspected we’d have to do something to our water for anything other than the darker beers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://agalewerks.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agalewerks.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Long ago, in a “previous life” both of us were medical laboratory professionals. Mixing reagents and growing bugs was something that I really enjoyed. Software development challenges and pay lured me away from the laboratory, but I have always sort of missed the precision of measuring, mixing, and testing.
When I would yen for tgit he good ol’ days in the lab, Silvia would suggest that I start home brewing beer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
